Hello programmer, welcome back to today's new tutorial series. So today here, we'll create
MySQL tutorial series. So today here, we'll create not null constant in the MySQL. It's the powerful
feature for ensuring data integrity in your database. Okay, so first of all, you'll simply just
explain for MySQL, not null constant. Okay, so in this constant is MySQL used to specify
that a column cannot contain null values. And this ensures that the record must have a
value for the column. Okay, so first of all here, I can create already the new table for here.
And here I can create for the total for column. So first on the ID and enter the primary key
and next step, I can create the title. Then here, I can apply for the not null constant and also
here the start date and both for the not null constant. Okay, and in this, so here is just introduction
and basically here, I'll create the table and here in this, the test table, exclusive
defined for this title and start date column of the not null constant and ID has primary
constant key. And therefore the implicit include for here, not null constant. Okay, so now
just here, I can select execute in this table data information. So first of all, select and execute,
and you can see the command is completely successful. Okay, so the next step here, insert,
so first step here, check the current null value and here, completely create for the verification
message for the command is completely successful. Okay, and the next step here, inserts. So now
in the section already cleared for here, I can insert for the sum row in the test table. So
here, into record users to provide an estimated and date when we're executing for here every new task
and you can add the not null constant to the ended column of the test table. Okay, so here,
this is completely cleared and now here, I can just use lastly define the null value. Okay,
so you can understand and next step here, I can define for the ID is one. Okay, and also here,
I can create this idea of queue. So here is completely just define and simply here,
I can just perfectly create the table information and now just like an egg in check and you can
see here the perfect now, I can just select all and execute and just to it and you can see here,
the two row is completely affected. Okay, so here, I create the confirmation message and here,
completely create this table information. Okay, and now, I can just find the for the row the nulls
in the column for the end date using for the null operator. Okay, so here, I can just open for
another new query and just verify for the task table. So first of all here, I can just type this,
the select, then describe from and here, I can just describe this test table. Okay,
so define perfectly and here, I can select and now perfectly execute and you can see here,
completely clear. So first is the ID, then title, then the started and then date and here,
then date is completely read for the null constant. Okay, and now here, I can create using for the
is null operator. Okay, the first of all, we are create the same, this null statement and then
here, I can use for the y clause. Okay, so y clause for the stock for underscore date. Okay,
and here, I can type for this is null. Okay, and then I can just change the use for the all
capital world. Okay, so here, this is completely used for this and here, I can apply for the semicolon.
Okay, so in this query, completely define this and now here, perfectly use the null operator and now
just paste it and we have taken the variable, so first of all, select the execute and here,
you can see here, the query is written for on row ordinal in the end column. Okay, and you can see
here, perfectly in the end column is perfectly null. And here, the start date and ID two with the
title for chicken update, but not constant to your database. Okay, so here, completely create and
also here, get the update null values to non null values and in this case, you can create a rule
for that said the on week after the date started when the end date is null. Okay, so here,
I can just apply for the update is greatly here, I can open another new query and first of all,
just type for this update for the test table. On the next step here, I can use the stage name
and now just type for here, this is the stage and here, I can just type for underscore
and then type for the date is equal to so start underscore date. Here, I can use for the class
operator for seven. Okay, and now just here, I can type this is one. So, just perfectly call
the one plus four and then we're going to the next step and I can just type for this is
suppose the end date for this norm. Okay, so now here, completely create in this stage name and
now just here, I can apply and just execute. So, just select an execute and you can see here
the date is incompatible with the integer. Okay, so now here, directly not defined for this stage name
and here, I can create for another way. So, now just go for again here. So, now just
go. So, now just go here and first of all here, I can use the ID for
Z3 and next year, I can apply for the code and here, insert, show another update. So,
first of all here, create is 20, 24, then here, apply for two months for the age. Okay,
so here completely create and select all and now just execute and you can see here completely
created the two row activate. Then here, just begin for select and execute this statement. So,
just a simpler remove and here, create the completely this element and then again,
if not saved here, the first of all, I can select all and execute. Now, I can see here,
completely just change for here, I can create with the new double column or inside it. Okay,
so double also here, integration completely done and here, perfectly apply the not null constant
in this section. Okay, so thank you for watching and happy coding.